Guide to the Cornell University School of Hotel Administration, Statler Hotel records, 1928-1988
Cornell University School of Hotel Administration, Statler Hotel records, 1928-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Statler Hotel records, 1928-1988.
28-3-1801
Cornell University. School of Hotel Administration. Statler Hotel.
5.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, records, financial statements, bulletins.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, files concerning Statler's new wing; construction and engineering publications; other records of Cornell's Statler Inn; financial statements; photograph; and Statler Inn registration cards for Harry Truman, Barry Goldwater, and Robert Kennedy.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence of Professor Charles I. Sayles; files concerning Statler's new wing, 1952-1959; correspondence regarding equipment; construction and engineering publications; and other records of Cornell's Statler Inn. Also, financial statements from the Statler Inn and Alice Statler Auditorium; photograph of Statler Hotel and Inn employees, Christmas, 1986; and "Statler Hotel and Conference Center Operating Criteria," 1987-1988.
Also Statler Inn registration cards for Harry Truman, April 20, 1960; Barry Goldwater, January 26-27, 1961; and Robert Kennedy, September 28-29, 1964.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Goldwater, Barry M.(Barry Morris), ‡d 1909-1998.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Sayles, C. I. (Charles I.).
Subjects:
Hotel management schools.; Hotels--Furniture, equipment, etc.; Taverns (Inns)--Furniture and equipment.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence regarding equipment
  - Professor Sayles pending file (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - All-Steel Equipment Co. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Gas Assoc. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aluminum Cooking Utensil Co. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Laundry Co. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anemostats (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bars - for Statler Hotel (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Barth Equipment Company (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bell Telephone Company (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - G.S. Blakeslee Company (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blankets (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from S. Blickman Company (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Blickman Company (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Blickman Food Service Equipment (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Statler Hotel Blueprint Distribution (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brandt, G.L. Company (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bulletin Boards (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "B" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carrier (insurance and air conditioning plus repairs to air conditioning) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Callis, H.B. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Capital Cubicle Company (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - C-O-2 Fire Equipment Company (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Colt's Manufacturing Company (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Conferences (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Mr. Connors (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Conveyors (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Convector-Radiators (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Counting devices (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cowper Company (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "C" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Drinking Fountain and Beverage Service (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "D" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Economics Laboratory, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Erskine Healy Company (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Purchasing Equipment List for Food Laboratories, 213, 219, and 216 Storage (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "E" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Finger Lakes Chemical Company (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "F" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - George, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - General Electric Supply Company (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Groen Manufacturing Company (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "G" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Hargraves, H.M. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Hobart Manufacturing Company (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Holabird Root and Burgee (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Humphrey's, Jack (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "H" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Ice Making (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - International Silver Company (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Jordan, J.J. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "J" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Light Fixtures - Details (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "L" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
  - "Mc/Mac" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Martin-Senour - color chart (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Mechanical Devices Specifications (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Murray and Sorensen (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - "M" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "N" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Onondaga Pottery Company (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Otis Elevator (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - "O" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - "P" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Robert's Products (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Room 104 - files (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Room 137 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Room 152 - Specifications (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Room 207 - Specifications (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Rugs (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - "R" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Savill Company (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Professor Sayles - Statler Hotel Specifications (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Scales (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Segdewick Company (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Sheldon Company (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Statler Hotel (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Statler Hotel - H.B. Meek (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - "S" - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Telephone - Statler Hotel (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Trumbull Electric Company (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "T" - miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Universal Electric Company (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Henry Vogt Company (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Volker Company (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "V" - miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Waterproofing Products Corporation (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Westinghouse Electric Company (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "W" - miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Zurn, J.A. Manufacturing Company (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Files
    - Addition to the Statler (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Banquet service (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Building codes (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Evans report, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Financial (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Indentures (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Inn (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Interior design (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - General
    - Montesano (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Ellsworth M. Statler (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - New Wing (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Letchworth (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Holabird and Root (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Buildings and grounds (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Studios (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - New Wing
    - New Wing (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - New wing miscellany (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A-Z correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Buildings and grounds (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Budget for new wing (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Auditorium and addition, Statler's will, etc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Organ and projector (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Floor plan (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Statler Hotel to July 1951
    - Notebook, Holabird and Root and Borgee, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
    - Buildings and grounds (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Blickman, S. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Callis, H.B. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - To Callis, H.B. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Statler Hotel Requirements
    - Suggestions and faculty requisitions (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Notes and comments on plans (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Requirements, July 1, 1942-January 24, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Scheme E (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Requirements prior to June 30, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Working papers (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Holabird and Root and Burgee (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Willard Straight Hall and Clara Dixon - dishwasher and sanitizer (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cornell Alumni Association (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Personal (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Open letter to packaging manufacturers (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Bulletins (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Office memo (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cornell Society of Scientists (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - School of Nutrition (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - C.I.S. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Equipment (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chlorinator (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chlorinator, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Water chlorinator (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Report on chamber expander (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 600.00 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 621.313.31 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - 621.313.32 Test procedures (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 621.313.31 Dielectric heating (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - 621.314 Commercial food processing machinery (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - 621.315 Water Softeners (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - 621.560 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - 621.561 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - 621.561 Large box construction (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - 621.562 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 621.563 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Alco Valve Co. Refrigerant Control Valves (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 621.57 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 621.576 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 621.590 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - 621.590.1 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 621.591 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 621.600 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 621.601 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 621.610 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 621.611 Instruments - R.H. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 621.612 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 621.613 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 621.613 MVTR (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - 621.566 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Filing - Refrigerators (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Miscellany (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Loose catalogs (Box 4)
    - Statler Inn financial statements, 1959-1978 (Box 5)
    - Memos about Sale of Beer in Willard Straight Hall, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Main Dining Room Department Training Manual - Statler Inn, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Statler Hotel Opening - 1986
    - Dedication of the Statler Addition - Photos, November 8, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Renderings of Statler Hotel and Conference Center, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Renderings - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Model - Photos, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Renderings - Hotel Lobby, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Renderings - Ground Hotel, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Renderings - First Floor Hotel, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Renderings - Second Floor Hotel, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Renderings - Main Dining Room, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Renderings - Private Dining Room, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Renderings - Banfi Dining Room, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Renderings - Ballroom, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Renderings - Private Meeting Room, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Renderings - Guestrooms, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Renderings - Faculty Club Entrance, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Renderings - Faculty Club Library, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Renderings - Faculty Office, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Samples - Photos, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Renderings - Marriott Executive Educational Center, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Building Plans, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Plans - West School Entry, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Academics Related to Building, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Renderings - Library Interior, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Plans - Ground Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Plans - First Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Plans - Second Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Plans - Third Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Plans - Fourth Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Plans - Fifth Floor School, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Renderings - Student Entrance, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Renderings - Student Lounge, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Renderings - Student Cafe, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Renderings - Development and Alumni Affairs Offices, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Renovation Fact Sheet, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)